cv.md 4/9/2023

Vadym Skliarov

C#/.NET Backend Software Engineer

sklyarov.vadym@gmail.com | Linkedin: Vadym Skliarov | Facebook: Vadym Skliarov

Summary

I am a software engineer with over 6 years of experience in designing, developing, documenting, and releasing complex software solutions using cutting-edge industry-standard tools and practices. I enjoy building good relationships with coworkers and tackling challenging problems as a united team.

Experience

- March 2015 May 2015 **C# Intern, Softheme, Kyiv**
- January 2019 July 2019 C#/.Net Backend Software Engineer, YouControl, Kyiv
- August 2019 November 2019 Software Developer, Eleks, Kyiv
- November 2019 till now
 Senior Developer, NCube, Kyiv
- March 2022 till now Ukrainian Armed Forces

Education

 2011—2015 BA in Computer Science, National Technical University of Ukraine 'Kyiv Polytechnic Institute', FICT

Skills

- C#: LINQ, async/await, .NET 5
- AWS: S3, SQS, EC2, Auto Scaling groups, CodeDeploy
- Microsoft Azure Services: Cosmos DB, Service Bus, Table Storage, Blobs, Azure Functions
- Git, TeamCity, GitHub
- MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Redis
- Python, Pandas, QGIS
- · Mentoring newcomers: code review, guiding through project architecture and involved technologies
- Team work, and ability, if necessary, to replace other team members

Level of competence

- C# 6 years of experience in commercial development, 8 years of experience overall
- ASP.NET Core designed, developed, and maintained APIs solutions
- AWS worked on a project built on AWS, managed resources, built CI\CD pipelines
- Python, QGIS used for pet-projects (web-scrapping, data-science, telegram bots)

cv.md 4/9/2023

Languages

- English C1 (TOEFL score 93 out of 120, passed in 2015)
- German B1
- Ukrainian native

Projects

• June 2015 - April 2018 Rapid Recovery on-premise backup solution

Our team designed and released a feature for backing up virtualized environments such as Hyper-V and VMware ESXi. As a member of the team, I was involved in designing, implementing, documenting solutions, and proposing ideas for new features.

• April 2018 - November 2018 Rapid Recovery SaaS Solutions

Our team was implementing a cloud-based administrator portal for managing Rapid Recovery on-premise backup solutions. I worked with cutting-edge technologies and architectural approaches e.g. microservice architecture, Azure Service Fabric, Cosmos DB, Azure Service Bus, and Azure Storage. My main responsibility was integration with on-premise solutions, improving the reliability of communication with cloud-based solutions, and mentoring newcomers(i.e. making code review, quiding them through project architecture and involved technologies).

• January 2019 - July 2019 YouControl

Our team designed and implemented solutions for scrapping, normalizing, and interconnecting data from multiple open sources. As a part of the team, I was responsible for designing our Web API, supporting our web-messenger bots, and scrapping and normalizing large amounts of data.

August 2019 - November 2019 Advisor360

I was working on a project, the main goal of which was to connect financial advisors with their customers to maximize incomes from their investments. As a part of a team, I was responsible for the process of product transition from single to multiple clients.

November 2019 - till now PublicNow

I was working on a system that monitors companies' news and press releases, extracts data from them, and delivers them to customers as quickly as possible. I was working on multiple services and apps which gathered, analyzed, categorized, normalized, and distributed data and was responsible for TFS to Git and CI/CD transition.